

#### Monika Gos, CPsychol

Clinical and Counselling Psychologist, EMDR and Brainspotting Therapy Practitioner, Focusing Oriented Psychotherapists and Clinical Consultant in Health City.

Health City, Davenport House, 16 Pepper Street, Canary Wharf, London E14 9RP. Tel: 0333 800 3006, 0333 789 0012. Email: <a href="mailto:info@healthcity.org.uk/">info@healthcity.org.uk/</a> Website: <a href="https://healthcity.org.uk/">https://healthcity.org.uk/</a>

My way of working is rooted in the belief that every person has the inner capacity for growth and healing. Deep attunement to a person's inner experience opens the doors to the depths of self and to life changing steps. Some of my specialty areas are: Attachment and early trauma with all its psychological consequences, eating disorders, body psychotherapy, hard to treat psychological conditions, substance abuse, lack of meaning and direction in life, as well as self-fulfillment, performance enhancement etc.

I am a Chartered Psychologist and an HCPC registered Clinical and Counselling Psychologist. I am also a Focusing-Oriented Psychotherapist and Focusing Trainer, and Brainspotting Trainer. I have studied: Focusing Oriented Relational Psychotherapy, Relational Psychoanalysis, EMDR, Core Energetics, Gestalt and NLP. I am a trainer and a clinical consultant at Health City.

#### **Professional Experience**

Jan 2010 – Present Clinical and Counselling Psychologist / Psychotherapist, Independent private practice, London, United Kingdom and internationally.

2016 – 2022 Clinical Psychologist- CGL Spectrum, Hertfordshire.

Assessing and treating addictions and the problems above and many more.

2015 - ongoing Expert Clinician, ProPhase - New York, USA

Expert Clinician for the Janssen CNTO program and ESKET studies
Providing remote Assessment of Depression with the Hamilton- HDRS-17/SIGH-D for the
CNTO trial- a double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicentre study of Sirukumab as Adjunctive
Treatment to Monoaminergic antidepressant in Adults with Major Depressive Disorder.
Providing remote Assessment of Depression with the Montgomery-Asberg Depression Rating
Scale (MADRS/SIGMA). ESKET studies test the safety and efficacy of Janssen's esketamine
compound in treatment of resistant depression. The trial is a randomized, double-blind,
multicentre, active-controlled study to evaluate the efficacy, safety and tolerability of fixed doses

of intranasal esketamine plus an oral antidepressant in adult subjects with treatment resistant depression.

#### 2010 - ongoing Clinical and Counselling Psychologist in private practice

Providing psychological and therapeutic services for both English and Polish speaking clients. Self-referrals and insurance referrals after accidents causing traumatic responses. Working with such symptoms as: anxiety, attachment issues and disorders, adjustment disorders, addictions, eating disorders. co-dependency, trauma, PTSD, personality disorders, Fibromyalgia, Chronic Fatigue Syndrome, Depression.

# 2012 – 2015 Counselling Coordinator, CRI – Drugs and Alcohol Services, Lewisham, London, UK

Responsible for organisation and management of the Counselling Service, Recruitment, Training and ongoing supervision for volunteer counsellors.

# 2010 – 2012 Counsellor, CRI – Drugs and Alcohol Services, Havering, London, UK

Responsibilities: provide Tier 3 treatment services; comprehensive assessment, determination of appropriate level of care; collaboration with other health care agencies, referrals, dual diagnosis, conduct educational and process-oriented group therapy; CBT, Motivational Interviewing and Trauma Focused treatment applied in individual therapy sessions, working within multi-disciplinary team.

# 2009 – 2010 Project Worker in DHP (Douglas House Project) Turning Point in conjunction with Oxleas NHS Foundation Trust/ Oxleas House, London, UK

Responsibilities: provide treatment and delivery of the Structured Day Programme for service users diagnosed with Severe Personality Disorders applying Mentalisation - based therapy for Borderline Personality Disorder in residential setting (pilot programme).

# 2007 – 2009 Substance Abuse Counsellor - Outreach Project Development Corp., New York, USA

Responsibilities: conduct group / individual therapy sessions, comprehensive assessment, determination of appropriate level of care, referrals and liaison with other health care professionals, working within the multidisciplinary team.

# 2004 - 2005 Internship - Department of Oncology, Academy of Medicine, Poznan, Poland

Responsibilities: providing support for patients awaiting surgery.

### 2003 – 2004 Internship - Mental Health Hospital, Mental Health Hospital, Poznan, Poland

Responsibilities: assessment, diagnosis and individual sessions with patients diagnosed with depression, bipolar affective disorder, psychotic disorders, anxiety, personality disorders and

learning disabilities.

#### **Professional Membership and Registration**

- Health and Care Professions Council (HCPC) registered Clinical and Counselling Psychologist
- The British Psychological Society (BPS) 264439
- The EMDR Association UK & Ireland
- The Focusing Institute, New York, USA
- The International Association of Focusing Oriented Psychotherapists
- A Partner Member of the Polish Psychologists' Association
- Auricular Acupuncturist certified by NADA, UK
- Deutscher Psychologen Verband, (DPV), Germany

#### **Education & Professional Training**

#### 2013 - 2014 Comprehensive Resource Model and Resource Brainspotting

Therapeutic method for working with dissociation and complex trauma; Berlin, Germany

#### 2013 – 2014 Training in Brainspotting

All levels of Training - brain-based treatment for trauma, anxiety, addictions, performance enhancement in sport and performing arts.

#### 2011 Training in Auricular Acupuncture; NADA; London, UK

Complementary therapy for addiction and stress management

#### 2010-2011 Training in EMDR (Eye Movement Desensitization and Reprocessing

All levels of training, Richman – EMDR Training, London, UK

#### 2008 - 2009 Training in Body Oriented Therapy

Core Energetics Institute, New York, USA

#### 2007 – 2009 Training in Focusing Oriented Relational Psychotherapy

Focusing Institute in New York, USA

#### 2005 – 2006 Training in Relational Psychoanalysis

Manhattan Institute for Psychoanalysis, New York, USA

#### 2002 – 2004 Training in Gestalt Therapy

Aion – The Centre for Psychotherapy, Poznan, Poland

#### 1999 – 2000 Training in Neurolinguistic Programming (NLP)

NLP Practitioner, Milton Erickson Institute, Berlin, Germany

#### 1999 – 2004 Masters Degree in Psychology, Clinical Psychology

Adam Mickiewicz University, Poznan, Poland

#### 1992 – 1998 Masters Degree in Music, Violin Master Class

Academy of Music, Poznan, Poland

1986 – 1992 A levels, major in Music

Secondary Music School, Violin Master Class, Stettin, Poland

Interests: Travelling, diving, playing and composing music.

**Languages:** Polish (mother tongue), English (fluent), German (working knowledge), Russian (working knowledge)

References available on request